<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>does-2023 on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/does-2023/</link><description>Recent content in does-2023 on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/does-2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DevOps Enterprise Summit - airport culture</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/devops_enterprise_summit_2023_wednesday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/devops_enterprise_summit_2023_wednesday/</guid><description>As I am sitting at Schipol Airport, contemplating that the airport is so big it has a branch of the Rijksmuseum, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but thinking about the fabulous conference I&amp;rsquo;ve just been to. The DevOps Enterprise Summit 2023 has exceeded my expectations. But before I get to there, I&amp;rsquo;d just like to develop the airport metaphor a little bit. So here I am, looking at culture.
Why was it that at Schipol, one of the busiest airports in the world, it was a breeze to get through security, airport security agents were smiling, cracking jokes, I could leave my laptop, toothpaste and deodorant in the bag and they have art in the middle of the airport, goddammit.</description></item><item><title>DevOps Enterprise Summit - simple paper cranes</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/devops_enterprise_summit_2023_tuesday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/devops_enterprise_summit_2023_tuesday/</guid><description>As I am sitting on the 16th floor of the Okura Hotel in Amsterdam in my Batman pyjamas and facing a large mirror, just glimpsing the paper crane that was so lovingly put on my pillow, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to reflect what has happened during the day. I was lucky enough to be a guest at the DevOps Enterprise Summit. There was certainly plenty of things to get excited about.
I&amp;rsquo;d meet Gene Kim, who&amp;rsquo;s been running this conference for 10 years and who wrote the Phoenix Project.</description></item></channel></rss>