<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bsides on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/bsides/</link><description>Recent content in bsides on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/bsides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BSides Newcastle 2025: Mission to Cyberspace</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/bsides_ncl_2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/bsides_ncl_2025/</guid><description>BSides Newcastle is probably one the most anarchic of the BSides I&amp;rsquo;ve been to so far. So much so that the fascists organised a protest. Well, not really, but there was a far-right and counter-protest not far from where the conference was. Thankfully, the organisers were on top of it and kept is all up-to-date with advice: &amp;ldquo;Punch Nazis&amp;rdquo; (for the benefit of the tape, nobody endorsed violence).
Aaanyway, aside from a really early start I was ready to dive in and hope to share some of the experiences with you.</description></item><item><title>BSides Newcastle 2023: Chaos for the future</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/bsides_ncl_2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/bsides_ncl_2023/</guid><description>After BSides Lancs and Leeds, Newcastle was my third BSides, both of the year and ever. I got up early in the morning for a road trip from Preston to Newcastle, and setting off at 5:30 on Saturday turned out to be atmospheric and straightforward. So I was a bit early and got a glimpse of the chaos that is putting together a BSides. Later I found out that BSides Newcastle was traditionally more chaotic than some of the other BSides.</description></item><item><title>BSides Leeds 2023: Get the basics right</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/bsides_leeds_2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/bsides_leeds_2023/</guid><description>It is a couple of weeks after my trip to Leeds to go speak at BSides. Now, if you&amp;rsquo;ve never been to a BSides - and I had only been to one prior - then hopefully this gives you a bit of a feel as to what to expect. In short, there&amp;rsquo;s lots of interesting people with great talks and insights and something that feels just right. A bit of community and some weird people.</description></item></channel></rss>