<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>weakly-link on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/weakly-link/</link><description>Recent content in weakly-link on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/weakly-link/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weakly Link 25/47</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/weakly_link_2025_47/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/weakly_link_2025_47/</guid><description>This week there have been some interesting bugs. Or interest in bugs.
Bugs It was Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s turn to break the internet. As per usual, the transparency on display is rather cool. It was rather interesting that for once, the problem wasn&amp;rsquo;t DNS or BGP, neither was it a cyberattack. Though indirectly, the threat of bots was responsible. As a subtle change in the handling of queries meant that the bot management system suddenly produced config files that were twice as large and that made them larger than the system could handle.</description></item><item><title>Weakly Link 25/46</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/weakly_link_2025_46/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/weakly_link_2025_46/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s edition of the weakly link has got some fire in it:
First on the menu we&amp;rsquo;ve got a report that tries to tell us that if there&amp;rsquo;s an AI bubble, that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing: The AI Wildfire Is Coming. It&amp;rsquo;s Going to Be Very Painful and Incredibly Healthy Instead of a bubble, the post tells us of one dinner guest at a CEO dinner in Silicon Valley who argues that instead of a bubble it is more like a wildfire.</description></item><item><title>Weakly Link 25/45</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/weakly_link_2025_45/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/weakly_link_2025_45/</guid><description>Every week I come across some interesting, ridiculous or astounding content related to security and tech around software engineering. And I post it on the company Slack, sometimes on LinkedIn and often on BlueSky or Mastodon. (I deleted my Twitter account a long time ago. No Nazi bar for me.)
And yet, I often forget all about the content. And because I closed my browser with 200ish open tabs once too often, I thought, why not write about the things that interested me, then I can look back on them and maybe someone else might find them interesting too.</description></item></channel></rss>