<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>genai on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/genai/</link><description>Recent content in genai on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/genai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BSides Newcastle 2025: Mission to Cyberspace</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/bsides_ncl_2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/bsides_ncl_2025/</guid><description>BSides Newcastle is probably one the most anarchic of the BSides I&amp;rsquo;ve been to so far. So much so that the fascists organised a protest. Well, not really, but there was a far-right and counter-protest not far from where the conference was. Thankfully, the organisers were on top of it and kept is all up-to-date with advice: &amp;ldquo;Punch Nazis&amp;rdquo; (for the benefit of the tape, nobody endorsed violence).
Aaanyway, aside from a really early start I was ready to dive in and hope to share some of the experiences with you.</description></item><item><title>Make it so: GenAI, OpenAPI and ZAP</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/make_it_so_genai_and_zap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/make_it_so_genai_and_zap/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered how hard it is to make an AI talk to an API? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if I could talk to a machine like Captain Picard does to his computer?
&amp;ldquo;Tea. Earl Grey. Hot!&amp;rdquo; would have to sent to the replicator subsystem with the correct instructions. But how would that actually work? I suppose, the Starship Enterprise-D made its first appearance on the airwaves in 1987. So at the time I guess we could expect a replicator to be programmed in C.</description></item></channel></rss>