<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>agile on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/agile/</link><description>Recent content in agile on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:32:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What makes a good developer</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/what_makes_a_good_developer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:32:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/what_makes_a_good_developer/</guid><description>A few days back as part of a general discussion about interviewing at Equal Experts, we looked at the question &amp;ldquo;What makes a good developer?&amp;rdquo; Could we come up with a list of qualities in a developer that we&amp;rsquo;d want to look for? This post illustrates my thinking.
Why do you ask? To put it in a bit of context, I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer, I&amp;rsquo;m not a recruiter, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with technical interviewing for quite a while, and have marked a fair number of take-home tests over the years, but recently we thought that the experience was not as good as it could be.</description></item><item><title>Record and publish your meeting</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/screen_record_meetings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 21:43:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/screen_record_meetings/</guid><description>Scenario: You&amp;rsquo;re in a handover session and explain everything in great detail but Dave is too hungover, Jim is on holiday and Jane is at another meeting and Chris isn&amp;rsquo;t asking any questions and in any case Trevor (who is actually going to be looking after this system after handover) hasn&amp;rsquo;t been recruited yet.
Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be useful to record the session and make it available? Now, this piece of writing does not explore whether we should be recording meetings, nor does it attempt to answer the question of whether good documentation wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be preferable to having to sit and spend hours watching someone droning on about something that could be condensed into a five minute read of a blog post.</description></item><item><title>The Shield and the Sword</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/the_shield_and_the_sword/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 15:40:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/the_shield_and_the_sword/</guid><description>To successfully deliver software a developer needs a shield and a sword.
A good product owner, delivery manager or alike that will shield the engineers from having to attend too many meetings, giving long-winded status updates and essentially allow them to get on with it. Shields go to all the meetings with the &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; and explain what can and cannot be done, without the engineer having to attend. A shield would also filter all the last-minute requirements or requests for gold plating without having to be dragged into endless meetings.</description></item><item><title>Making Software. Quickly.</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/making_software_quickly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 08:54:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/making_software_quickly/</guid><description>In this post, I describe my personal experience of being part of a software development team working with Equal Experts and HMRC during Covid-19. Under normal circumstances, we&amp;rsquo;re responsible for tax services such as Self Assessment, PAYE Expenses and Benefits, VAT submissions amongst others. These services run on the Multi-channel Digital Tax Platform (MDTP). This platform is hosted in a hyperscale cloud (the cloud provider has a sideline selling books), run in-house by HMRC teams made up of permanent staff and consultants.</description></item></channel></rss>