<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>my-take-on on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/my-take-on/</link><description>Recent content in my-take-on on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 03:30:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/my-take-on/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Less is more agile</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/my_take_on_engineering_room_9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 03:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/my_take_on_engineering_room_9/</guid><description>Dave Farley and Allen Holub are two people that I respect hugely when it comes to Software Development. I&amp;rsquo;ve been following them on twitter for quite a while, and am always taken in about their takes on driving continuous delivery and &amp;ldquo;lowercase agile&amp;rdquo; forward. So when both came together for Dave&amp;rsquo;s Engineering Room (sponsored by Equal Experts, who I work with), it was bound to be very interesting.
In this post I try to outline my key takeaways from watching the chat.</description></item><item><title>On the weaponisation of open source</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/on_weaponisation_of_open_source/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 14:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/on_weaponisation_of_open_source/</guid><description>First of all I need the preface this article on how much I abhor the Russian invasion of Ukraine and I wholeheartedly support the sanctions. However, I think the conflict has spilled over into areas of software development that have got some unintended consequences attached.
As part of this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to look at
the decision by MongoDB to cut off services in Russia the destructive change in a node library that deleted files on Russian IPs a change in code/licence in a community terraform module to assert that Putin is a dickhead MongoDB cutting off Russian customers MongoDB is a company and in order to comply with sanctions they have decided to cut off Russian customers.</description></item><item><title>Context and Lines - My Take on Engineering Room Ep 1</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/my_take_on_engineering_room_1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 16:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/my_take_on_engineering_room_1/</guid><description>Dave Farley and Martin Fowler are two heavyweights when it comes to Software Development. As well as his latest and hugely anticipated book Modern Software Engineering, Dave wrote Continuous Delivery. Martin co-wrote the Agile Manifesto and Refactoring. All of which are hugely influential to large swathes of software engineers. So when both came together for Dave&amp;rsquo;s new series on YouTube, the Engineering Room (sponsored by Equal Experts), it was bound to be very interesting.</description></item></channel></rss>