<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>agile-india on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/agile-india/</link><description>Recent content in agile-india on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 23:30:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/agile-india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What do you think are the most exciting developments in software product engineering today?</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/agile_india_2022_speaker_interview_questions_3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 23:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/agile_india_2022_speaker_interview_questions_3/</guid><description>This is part of my series of interview questions for Agile India 2022.
Thinking about exciting developments in software development as a developer immediately brings magpies to mind. What is the latest technology that can grab our attention. What&amp;rsquo;s the latest shiny? Could it be some crypto tech? Some no-code development? Or programming in the metaverse maybe?
No, no, and NO! Crypto is a scourge that wastes energy, kills the planet and destroys lives, no-code and low code will mean some actual software engineers will have to pick up the pieces when it inevitably will go wrong and the metaverse (second second life) looks to be a great way to make the web as tedious to use than going to an actual shop where you can&amp;rsquo;t find anything because the items have moved to another shelf yet again.</description></item><item><title>What do you think is the biggest challenge faced by the software product engineering community today?</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/agile_india_2022_speaker_interview_questions_2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 03:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/agile_india_2022_speaker_interview_questions_2/</guid><description>This is part of my series of interview questions for Agile India 2022.
It is difficult to articulate what the biggest challenge to software product engineering is, because there&amp;rsquo;s a fair few of them, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to describe a few of my bug bears.
Process over people In my opinion, a huge issue that we unfortunately find all too often is when the principles of the agile manifesto are ignored or not applied.</description></item><item><title>What got you started in modern software development methods?</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/agile_india_2022_speaker_interview_questions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 02:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/agile_india_2022_speaker_interview_questions/</guid><description>After being accepted for speaking at Agile India 2022 I was asked a few questions. I figured rather than a paragraph, the questions would make interesting blog posts:
I came to agile completely the wrong way. I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing software professionally since I was a teenager and was lucky enough to start out with projects where I was given plenty of agency to decide on how to tackle problems and the independence to make my own mistakes and learn from them.</description></item></channel></rss>