<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>conference on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/conference/</link><description>Recent content in conference on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DevOps Enterprise Summit - simple paper cranes</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/devops_enterprise_summit_2023_tuesday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/devops_enterprise_summit_2023_tuesday/</guid><description>As I am sitting on the 16th floor of the Okura Hotel in Amsterdam in my Batman pyjamas and facing a large mirror, just glimpsing the paper crane that was so lovingly put on my pillow, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to reflect what has happened during the day. I was lucky enough to be a guest at the DevOps Enterprise Summit. There was certainly plenty of things to get excited about.
I&amp;rsquo;d meet Gene Kim, who&amp;rsquo;s been running this conference for 10 years and who wrote the Phoenix Project.</description></item><item><title>The agile power of saying no</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/notes_from_a_small_conference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 17:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/notes_from_a_small_conference/</guid><description>I am sitting on the train as I type this coming back from my first IRL conference. Lean Agile Scotland 2022 was brilliant. I met so many people with ideas that just chime with my thinking on agile, I feel energised and full of ideas
No Bugs No Decisions No Deadlines No Fear What follows are some thoughts that I took away from some of sessions the conference. There were lots of exciting talks and workshops and it was a pity that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t clone myself to go to more of them (I was gutted to miss sessions that coincided with my own talk).</description></item></channel></rss>