<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kotlin on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/kotlin/</link><description>Recent content in kotlin on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/kotlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI-dvent of Code 2023: Day 3</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/advent_of_code_2023_day_3_ai_experiments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/advent_of_code_2023_day_3_ai_experiments/</guid><description>My experimentation with LLMs on day 1 and day 2 of Advent of Code was a bit frustrating. For the day 3 puzzle, I decided to change model. Previously I had been using the codellama:13b model but wasn&amp;rsquo;t really happy. I kept arguing with it and it just frustrated me. So let&amp;rsquo;s try some others.
codellama:34b So I thought maybe the model just wasn&amp;rsquo;t big enough, so off we went</description></item><item><title>AI-dvent of Code 2023: Day 2</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/advent_of_code_2023_day_2_ai_experiments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/advent_of_code_2023_day_2_ai_experiments/</guid><description>After day 1 of Advent of Code was only partially successful, I thought I would change my approach. Yesterday I tried to get the LLM to develop the whole solution in one go. But that was more like argumentative programming rather than conversational programming, so for the day 2 puzzle I start with small problems and hope to put it all together at the end.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started The problem looked quite straightforward, parse something like the following</description></item><item><title>AI-dvent of Code 2023: Day 1</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/advent_of_code_2023_day_1_ai_experiments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/advent_of_code_2023_day_1_ai_experiments/</guid><description>So it is that time of the year again. Advent of Code is back. Yey! This means I get to try to look at a new language again. This time, why not Kotlin? But as an extra challenge, I thought why not see how the vaunted LLMs would help. Is AI really the accelerator that would elevate a mere developer to a rockstar ninja (whatever that is)?
I have to add that I am a bit of an AI sceptic and keep saying that</description></item></channel></rss>