<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>open-source on Tales about Software Engineering</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/tags/open-source/</link><description>Recent content in open-source on Tales about Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Software Design Systems</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beny23.github.io/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>XZ Backdoor: Not the End of Open Source</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/xz_backdoor_is_not_the_end_of_open_source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/xz_backdoor_is_not_the_end_of_open_source/</guid><description>When I stumbled across a post that an encryption library offers a potential backdoor to SSH connectivity on Good Friday, my first thought was: why is it always on a Friday that these things drop? And then my second one: oh bugger, here goes my weekend. Now, I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the technical details, there are many, many, many, many better resources out there, but I can&amp;rsquo;t help thinking that this would/should force the software industry to think.</description></item><item><title>On the weaponisation of open source</title><link>https://beny23.github.io/posts/on_weaponisation_of_open_source/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 14:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beny23.github.io/posts/on_weaponisation_of_open_source/</guid><description>First of all I need the preface this article on how much I abhor the Russian invasion of Ukraine and I wholeheartedly support the sanctions. However, I think the conflict has spilled over into areas of software development that have got some unintended consequences attached.
As part of this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to look at
the decision by MongoDB to cut off services in Russia the destructive change in a node library that deleted files on Russian IPs a change in code/licence in a community terraform module to assert that Putin is a dickhead MongoDB cutting off Russian customers MongoDB is a company and in order to comply with sanctions they have decided to cut off Russian customers.</description></item></channel></rss>